Describing the Essence of Value Creation
Welcome back to this session on value creation.
What we’re going to do is look at an implied example here, to help us better understand that.
Now remember, we can use value creation at a personal level,
as well as a professional level.
Now, we looked at a very rudimentary type of personal example,
when we applied it to the newspaper in kind of a got a joking way.
With the dog, eating the newspaper thereby restraining us
from having an opportunity to get a job.
Now what we’re going to do is look it at a professional level.
In this case we’re going to use a little product example. To make it very clear and succinct.
Essentially, let's imagine that we've got a product out there.
A piece of hardware. Could be an electronic device. We’ve talked about that before.
And it's full of CTQ’s.
So, that has got critical to quality characteristic 1 to critical to quality characteristic N.
That makes up that product.
Everything from the performance of it at the system level,
down to how well all the little resistors and diodes and everything else works.
Those are all critical to quality.
Well, it's a pretty simple little way to go. We’re going to pick a CTQ.
We’re going to call it CTQ sub Y.
Whatever that one could be, the first one, the fourth one, the fifth one. Who cares?
So, as we start to look at this,
we recognize again the simple steps.
We have to recognize the value need. Now, what's the value need?
That is the performance
of this CTQ. That's the utilitarian need.
So, that is in fact
the value need that we have is the performance of this CTQ.
So, if we look on a scale of performance. This is the scale of performance.
This might be how far out you can talk on that walkie-talkie.
See. That could be, you know, 500 feet, 600, 700, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Up here to a mile away.
So, what the basic situation is,
is that now we've gotta define that change opportunity.
We've got to take it maybe from here to there.
From an is condition to some ought condition, on that scale.
That's what we need to go do. So, that's the value need.
Performance of CTQ Y, which is a utilitarian need.
Which is a functional need. Remember that? Form, fit and function. This is function.
And we recognize that this is the current, and this is what ought to be.
And we gotta drive it from there to there.
Now, what we need to do is to define the change opportunity. That's that.
We’ve got to translate it from a product issue into a process issue.
In other words, we have to now start to talk about, in step two,
defining the change opportunity to talk about yield.
So, here's yield, 70, 80, 90, oops, 100.
So, we might currently have a yield of 80%.
That's the current. That's the is condition.
We may need to take it to 90%.
At this level of performance. See, at the ought right now, only 80% are being created.
But we need 90% at that level. So, I translated this now, to a process problem.
Improve the yield.
Now, step three is to measure the existing conditions.
So, I go out there and I measure it and I confirm, yeah, 80%.
That's the way it is right now. That's the is condition.
There’s my goal, over at 90%.
Now, what I gotta go do is step number four. Analyze the contributing forces.
I gotta recognize that sitting out there, in the process.
Recall, that I got a process here. Step one, two, three, and out here it creates my product.
I gotta improve my yield from the baseline of 80% to 90%.
Now, how am I going to do that?
I gotta go out here and look at all the X’s, X1, X2, X3
to XN, in the process. I gotta go look at all the process variables.
These are the knobs. Remember that. These are the knobs in the process
These are the knobs in the process that controls how good the yield is going to be.
So, I gotta go identify these through brainstorming, and then analyze them.
I need to look at which of those X's is driving me
toward my 90% goal and which is restraining me from that.
In other words, which of these is my vital few and which is the trivial many?
Then what I gotta go do is for every single one of those.
I’ll pick one of them with leverage.
Remember, some of these are among the vital few and most are among the trivial many.
I go find the vital few. That's what I got. I got the vital few drivers,
and I got the vital few restrainers.
Now, I’m going to take one of those X’s. The big hitter.
And I'm going to say that its force is from here to here.
Now, what I want to do is put an extension on that force. I want to make more force.
So, I need to increase the force of that variable.
Which might be training of my people, for example. They may not be well enough trained.
So, I need to increase the training.
See. That's one of the critical X’s.
That is a critical to process variable.
That is a contributory force.
So I need to go increase it, see, from there to here. I need to make that a stronger force.
They need to get more knowledge. If they get more knowledge.
What it’s going to do is push the situation in a more positive direction.
Getting me closer to my goal of 90%.
Which ultimately gets more performing at this ought condition.
Which satisfies the originating need.
Now, after I improve that action setting.
That variable that we looked at called training.
See, I took it from there and I extended it. I improved it. I made it bigger.
Before. After.
Now, what I gotta do is keep that from varying. In other words, I gotta sustain the gains.
I recognize that there's variation around these points.
So, I want to minimize the variation, so I get consistency of application of training.
I need to remove those variations.
Then I need to control those input variations over time.
I need to control those things that create the variation around training. Get rid of them.
For example, instructor to instructor differences in philosophy in teaching style,
causes the training to vary.
As the training varies, the force of my people, my workforce varies.
As it varies, I become less certain that I’m going to go from 80 to 90%.
So, that's what we mean by control input variations.
And then finally I look across everything that I did
in those six steps from step 1, 2, 3 through step 6, that I did.
Recall what those were. Recognize value needs. Define change opportunities.
Through those first six steps. And I say, what made it successful?
Well I standardize on those success factors.
Try to apply it to my other processes.
In other words, if training gotta bump on yield in this process,
well, let me go take that and try other processes.
If it works, standardize on it
and then integrate that lesson learned back into new policies and procedures.
So, that's ultimately how we move forward
with improving a critical to quality characteristic
which helps me satisfy a value need.
That's what value creation is all about.
It's a simple process consisting of eight steps.
That's how we do it, to create value. That's what value creation is all about.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.